

SUMMARY

Versatile, personable media professional prepared to transfer effective analytical and steadfast troubleshooting skills as well as a swift capacity to learn new technologies honed during 22 years as a Production Assistant and Broadcast Technician to a career as a Software Developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Coding: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap, GitHub
- Video Editing: Beta, DVCPRO, SSD, XDCAM, Blu-ray, Avid Media Composer, Final Cut Pro, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Media Encoder, DaVinci Resolve, iMovie
- Software Installations: Windows, macOS, ChromeOS, Linux, Android, iOS, Router, Modem, Printer/Scanner/Copier,
 IP Camera, Laptop Screen
- Hardware Upgrades: RAM, Hard Drive, Solid State Drive, Power Supply, DC-In Board, Optical Drive, Bluetooth/Wi-Fi Card
- Miscellaneous: Bug Fixes, Data Recovery, Malware Removal, Hard Drive Cloning, Cell Phone Rooting/Jailbreaking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KVUE TV - ABC, AUSTIN, TX

STUDIO FLOOR MANAGER, AUGUST 2022 — PRESENT

- · Oversee activity on the studio floor during newscasts to support smooth broadcasts.
- Direct the movement and positioning of on-camera talent to ensure proper placement in alignment with planned broadcast times.
- Prepare floor setups for routine and special edition broadcasts.
- Collaborate with other media staff to supervise floor activity, providing assistance with tasks as needed.
- Support broadcasting operations to maintain adherence to timelines and minimize interruptions.

KVUE TV - ABC, AUSTIN, TX

BROADCAST TECHNICIAN/MASTER CONTROL OPERATOR, MAY 2012 — AUGUST 2021

- Monitored and controlled on-air programming for all station-owned channels to ensure quality and accuracy of all broadcasts.
- · Operated multiviewer systems, equipment banks, and control panels to direct live broadcasts.
- Certified adherence of all broadcast content to established government guidelines.
- Controlled and dynamically adjusted incoming and outgoing broadcast signals utilizing switchers or automation to regulate sound volume as well as signal strength and clarity.
- Identified and rapidly troubleshot malfunctions during broadcasts to minimize interruptions.
- Documented malfunctions by submitting reports and logs, following up on issues as needed.
- Demonstrated an in-depth understanding of satellite, microwave, and other transmitter equipment to effectively broadcast television programs.
- Outperformed expectations, receiving recognition as Production Employee of the Year in 2013.
- Aligned objectives and bridged communications between media providers, sales, traffic, and marketing teams to secure scheduled playback, acquire, then input commercials and shows to the sever.
- Organized the execution of short recorded news segments.
- Recorded, encoded, and edited daily promotional teases in preparation for broadcasts.
- Managed activities on the studio floor by directing on- and off-camera staff to necessary positioning.
- Reported department maintenance issues to ensure timely resolutions.
- Curated quality broadcasts by displaying chyron show graphics, controlling manual and robotic cameras, commanding the audio board, and operating the teleprompter to provide lines.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

KEYE TV - CBS, AUSTIN, TX, OCTOBER 2011 — MAY 2012 | VIDEO EDITOR

ROYAL CARIBBEAN INTERNATIONAL, CAPE CANAVERAL, FL, JULY 2011 — SEPTEMBER 2011 | BROADCAST TECHNICIAN

MML Page 2

KOKH – FOX 25 News, Oklahoma City, OK, March 2007 — July 2011 | AUDIO OPERATOR/VIDEO EDITOR

KAUZ - CBS News Channel 6, Wichita Falls, TX, June 2004 — February 2007 | PRODUCTION ASSISTANT

KFDX - NBC TV-3, WICHITA FALLS, TX, JULY 2000 — APRIL 2004 | PRODUCTION ASSISTANT

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS (B.A.) IN ART, 2005

Midwestern State University, Wichita Falls, TX

CERTIFICATES

INTRODUCTION TO CODING, 2021

SheCodes.io

INTRODUCTION TO WEB DEVELOPMENT, 2023

SheCodes.io

WEB DEVELOPMENT, 2022

SheCodes.io

ADVANCED WEB DEVELOPMENT, 2023

SheCodes.io

ADVANCED REACT DEVELOPMENT, 2022

SheCodes.io

RESPONSIVE DEVELOPMENT, 2022

SheCodes.io

ADVANCED RESPONSIVE DEVELOPMENT, 2023

SheCodes.io

CAREER DEVELOPMENT, 2023

SheCodes.io

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT, 2023

SheCodes.io